and the next one also is almost well I
would stop and ask you to explain these
words to me a little bit more because I
have this the question is what is eco
modest modernism in left acceleration
ISM how does it envisaged that
technological process will allow us to
address climate and ecological breakdown
and I have to admit that I get a little
bit triggered when I when I see these
ISM words and one of my mentors and and
friends Satish Kumar who is the founder
of true Maha College where I learned a
lot of my initial understanding that
that has helped me for the last 20 years
when I did the Masters in holistic
science in 2001 Satish says every ism
creates a schism and and that means that
whether it's capitalism socialism or
environmentalism they all create a box
that you can either put your friends in
or your enemies in and then you don't
have to listen to them anymore then you
can just say ah yeah that is an eco
modernist and it into eco modernism I'm
not into that so I stopped listening or
socialist or capitalist and so if you
want you can can explain to me what what
you mean by left acceleration ISM or
equal modernism but but for me I think
we they're the bigger invitation behind
this question is to stop trying to put
people into these boxes and to really
listen to where each individual is
coming from and I I assume what eco
modernism is is speaking to us is this
mindset of technology will save the
world and if we find the right equal
technology or regenerative technology
then everything will be fine forever
after um it's probably the like recently
in social media there's this
the wrong kind of green movement that is
a again dismissing a lot of approaches
of trying to begin to walk the path
towards a regenerative impact as them
are going deep enough there to
technological that just the the elites
buying into this discourse now and
trying to co-opt it and yes we need to
we need to be vigilant about both
processes of co-option but I think we we
don't have time to stop
quite so drastically listening to each
other and just fight one ism against
another so I really stop if somebody
wants to explain what what you
understand with on the left
acceleration is then I might be able to
say something about it but I don't know
what this term refers to so shall we
just skip it okay I think the more the
main point I made in the beginning is is
let's let's be careful of making it so
easy to each other to stop listening
what the other everybody and certainly
me included and will as you bring in
something new as you bring in a positive
impulse we're all trapped in the
language traps and the thought traps of
the habits of the past and so everything
new will still have a little bit of the
the old left over there what doesn't
serve anymore and and so really the the
invitation is to always listen to the
wisdom in what the other person might be
sharing
their perspective and and not fall into
the trap of just looking for the one
thing that we can then categorize what
they're saying into our yeah he's coming
from back angle he's an eco modernist so
I can stop listening and dismiss him out
right and and and make it easier for
myself I think that's that's the main
point that I would like to make to that
question